# Trista McCleary

CodeAndCoffeeLife.com
github.com/mccleary
linkedin.com/in/tristamccleary

404-376-2653 Atlanta,Ga trista\_mccleary@yahoo.com

## **Summary**

Strongly detail-oriented person with a love for organization and eager to apply those skills to web development. I am excited to continue to grow my web development skills and am looking for employers who make my continued learning a priority. Ideally, I'd like to work on a team of developers who enjoy their craft, are building interesting software, and who are open to mentoring and developing new talent. I am an eternal student and it's exciting to me that there is so much out there to learn, and I look forward to continuing to add to my skill set for many years to come.

## **Projects**

#### **FITLIFE**

FitLife is a fitness eCommerce site designed to help those looking to learn how to eat properly, get healthy and lose weight. Meal plans are offered for both men and women. Look for workout plans coming soon! This project was made with the MEAN stack(JavaScript, jQuery, Node, Express, Angular, MongoDB)

Github: github.com/mccleary/fitlife

Demo: http://fitlifeforlife.us:5000/#/

#### **AIRNAV**

AirNav is an Atlanta Airport Navigation web application designed to help Atlanta airport travelers navigate through the world's busiest airport. This was a week long project built with a scrum team of four developers using agile development methodologies. Technologies used: HTML/CSS, Python, Angular, Leaflet, Sketch. \*My class group won "Best App"!

Github: https://github.com/DigitalCrafts-September-2016-Cohort/the\_a\_team2

Demo: https://airnavatl.com/#/home

#### **GETCOHORT**

GetCohort is a Coding Bootcamp app built to showcase each student's projects and contact info as well as links to their email, portfolio, github and linkedIn sites. This was a week long project built with a scrum team of four developers using agile development methodologies. Technologies used: HTML/CSS, Python, Flask, PostgreSQL. \*My class group project tied for second place!

Github: https://github.com/DigitalCrafts-September-2016-Cohort/GetCohort

Demo: http://54.148.11.254/ (for testing - user: juan.cortes@gmail.com | pass: 1)

## **Education**

DigitalCrafts, Ga - Certificate, Full Stack Web Development (2017)

Clayton State University, Ga - AAS, Computer Networking (2006)

Clayton State University, Ga - Certificate, Computer Network Technician (2005)

Clayton State University, Ga - BBA, Business Management (2003)

### Skills

- HTML5
- CSS3
- Python
- PostgreSQL
- Flask
- Sketch
- InVision

- JavaScript
- jQuery
- ÁngularJS
- ExpressJS
- Node.jsMongoDB
- Adobe Photoshop

## **Experience**

#### INSIDE SALES REP/PROCESSING SPECIALIST/INFRA-CHAMPION, INFRA-METALS - 2011-2015

- Handled three of the largest processing accounts in the company, retained highest gross margin profit. Inventory control with a focus on raw materials, customer fabricated parts.
- Manage job quotations and tracking process while focusing on driving company's margin product line. Responsible for account development and new business prospecting in a highly competitive market.
- Software Trainer, Key contributor for systems integration for Eniteo software system. Train current and future coworkers in all departments on how to use Eniteo for their department. Also, ongoing help desk support for all coworkers.
- Perform general sales functions -quotes, create job bids using T27 System based on duration of project length, data entry of sales, customer, quotes and invoices, apply industry knowledge, policies and procedures for questions and concerns posed while ensuring safety, scheduling of trucks with other departments to ensure commitment to the customer/client, Carbon Steel, Stainless, Aluminum.

#### **SOUTHEAST SENIOR BUYER, DIETRICH METAL FRAMING - 1998-2010**

- Provided direction and leadership for more than 20 company buyers of manufacturing consumables; contained and reduced costs through successful price negotiations and vendor management, aided in efficient operation of purchasing policies and procedures, and ensured conformance to company purchasing objectives and policies.
- Achieved cost reduction of 10.5% (\$85K in six months) by identifying inventory efforts and managing reduction of manufacturing expenses through vendor consolidation, renegotiation of service contracts, freight reductions, and changing items being purchased.
- Consistently maintained supply chain flow, thus minimizing downtime and maximizing productivity. Software Trainer, Managed and trained buyers in Oracle, I-Procurement, Contempus, SOX compliance. Managed buyers for ten facilities in the Southeast and Midwest and purchased supplies for four facilities; provided back up purchasing for 25 additional locations.

## **Professional Organizations**

PyLadiesATL - Member (Fall 2016 - present)

Women Who Code Atlanta - Member (Fall 2016 - present)